


💢 Class 3:

👉.NET Framework
 ☛Class Library: Library of code Microsoft developed to take care of difficult tasks. Ex:maths, dates, times etc.
 ☛Runtime or Common Language Runtime(CLR):Protective Bubble which shelter the application, which runs inside of clr too. It takes care of low-level details
then the software developer can focus on what the application is suposed to do.The clr provides protections for the end user (against for example bad intentionated developers)

👉Curly Braces ({}): Defines a code block.
👉Dot (.): It serves to gap c# references.
👉Parenthesis(()): It says we want to reference the class method and It serves to Invoke, Execute, Run some code, information(both arguments) and complement the class, and it serves as input parameter.
👉Semicolon(;): Declares a complete thought in c#, with this you can even do all the commands in the same line just putting the semicollons when a thought is done.

👉Not less Important:
 ☛In c# you have blocks of codes that reside inside of other blocks of code

💢Class 4:

👉Solutions: is where all the projects stay, they have a important function of sometimes relating projects.
 ☛Each solutions has its projects, there isn't only one soluction.

👉Projects: is where all the information and things of the program are stored.
👉Everything in the visual studio is stored in some part of your harddrive, you can open the solutions by opening the .sln projects in the stored place.
👉If you need to search anything about the soluction directory, you should open the solution file  and the csproj as notepad.
👉Bin:is where the debug is temporarily stored, since you execute your aplication.

💢Class 5
👉Variable: it's a kind of "bucket" where values of a certain type are stored.
 ☛We can put, values into a variable, change, and retrieve values.
 ☛There are a lot of types of variables, just variables that store giant numbers as variables that store small numbers.
 ☛When declaring a variable, always make it human-readable, always try to use names that make sense.
👉Assignment: the word refered to the action of assigning a value into a variable. Ex of assignment operators: "=".
👉Retrievement: to refer to an existent variable again, using this variable for something.
👉Concatenation: to "unify" a string that is being writing, with a variable. Ex of concatenation operators: "+"
👉Camel-case:to make the first word of a variable lower case, than you can distinguish it from programming commands(makes it human-readable).
👉Lower-case:c# is lower-case, which means every capitalization in the words matter.

💢Class 6
👉Sometimes is need to make codes that lets the user choose diferent ways during the execution.
👉If: A condition statement that chooses a condition for something(ex: variable), if this conditions is true, the code will be executed. Ex:if (PeopleNumber = 7000000000) {  ~~Random code~~; }
☛The operator of the if condition statement is the "==", which compares something to a value.
☛Else condition statement:When the condition of the if is not attendend, you can use a else to go to another if statement, you can either choose an empty else that will have no conditions after it( Catch off) (Ex: Else { ~Random Code~ } 
or you can choose an else with right an if with a condition (Aditional evaluations) (Ex:else if (~Random condition~) { ~random code~ }
☛If there's only one line of code after the if or the else condition statement, it's not necessary to use "{}" (Curly Braces).
👉Scope: Code Block (Uses the { } ).
☛It's not possible to declare two variables of the same name EVEN if this variable is in the inner of a scope.
👉Condition Operators:They do the same thing of the if condition statement, but they can only compare if ONE thing has the condition attendend and it can only have ONE else, and its else is only catch off, can't be aditional evaluations.
☛They are used like this: string RandomDeclaration = RandomDeclaration2 == RandomValue ? RandomValue2 :RandomValue3
☛The ? operator gets in its front the value that should go to the variable if the condition is attendend, the : operator gets in its front the value that should go if the condition is NOT attended.
☛In the RandomDeclaration it can be used () in it too.
☛It's only possible to use it in assignments
👉"{0}":It's used to get easier concatenation, a variable that was put after the string with a {0}, in the final print, will be written this variable in the place of the {0} Ex:Console.WriteLine("You won a {0} you're lucky", message");
in this case, if the message is equal to = boat, for exemple, the final written string would be = "You won a boat you're lucky
☛You can put multiples {0}, but, if you put multiples the second wil need to be {1} and the third {2}, and i like this eventually, and you need to put all the variables, if there are more than 1 {0} you can't use "+" operator, only ","

💢Class 7
👉Statement: What you call a complete tought in c# to complete one line of code.
☛Expressions:Are what stay in the statements, like operators and operands.
 ☛Operator: is what in c# makes an action/ function, acts on the operand to perform some action. can be compared to a verb.
   ☛Operand: It's the name you give for thins is c# like variables, database, classes and other plenty of things.. can be compared to subject.

💢Class 8
👉For loop statement: It's a loop statement that takes as arguments an existent or new int which is the int will, the condition for the loop keep going and the increment operand. its structure is like: for(int a = 0; a < 10;++a){}
☛The int stated in the for is specially for the loop, then you don't need to just create another one.
👉Break Statement:it is used to stop a loop, independent of the conditions are or aren't attended.

💢Class 9	
👉Array: a collection of data in c#, like a collection of variables of the same type,Declaration: int[] numbers = new int[5];
☛The part int[] indentifies that the type is int, and the [] identify that is a array, numbers is the operand, and the second part is the assignment, the new int[5], the new is to say the array is new, the [5] is to identify how many
elements the array has, the first element start with the number 0
☛To identify what each element of the array values you apply like this: array[0] = 2; array[1] = 6; array[2] = 3; array[3] = 10; array[4] = 50;
☛To retrieve to a specific element of the array you use like this: Console.WriteLine(numbers[1]);
☛To see the lenght of the array you do like this: numbers.length, exemple: Console.WriteLine(numbers.Length);
☛A way to not declare in time how many elements you want in your array is to set the values right in the assignment of your array, ex: int[] numbers = new int[]{12,13}, 12 is the 1st element, 13 the 2nd and like this successively.
☛A very good way to use a loop with a collection is the use the Foreach Interation statement

👉Foreach Iteration Statement:It serves to loop trough a collection of data. Ex: foreach(string name in Games){Console.Writeline(name)} The string name are the data inside the collection, the in Games is the collection, in this case, it
would loop through all this array and it would write each string in it.
👉Char: a type of variable that stores only one character, different of the array that stores a lot of characters.
👉ToCharArray: copies a string and makes it into an array of characters.
👉Array.Reverse: reverses all the characters in a char array.

💢Class 10
👉Method: Is a block of code that can be retrieved again, making it useful for codes that you need to use a lot of times. Ex: public static void Example(){ RandomCode;} to call this method you would do Example();
 ☛Input parameter:Something, like a variable, that's created inside of method parenthesis, making that when this method is called, this call need to give a value to this method, putting this value in parenthesis ()
 ☛Void:Means that nothing will be returned to the method that was created.
 ☛Return values can be used in a method to return a value of a specifc type in your method,ex of ways to return:string message = "hello guys; private static string "<- the return type" MethodEx(string message){message += "ty";
 return (message2)}, then the method can be used as values.
 ☛Another method call be called inside another method, as long as this called metod don't have a void return type and have a variable return type.
 ☛Two methods can have the same names, but can't have the same input parameters.
this string, i return this value to this method, and this will be my method return, ex of ways to return:string message = "hello guys; private static string <- the return type MethodEx(message){message += "ty"; return (message).
👉String.Concat(array): it concatenates all chars of an array and make it into a string.
👉Format():Creates a new screen of whatever have been formatted.

💢Class 11
👉While Iteration Statement:It's an Iteration Statement that keep looping through a code until a custom condition is attendend, ex; while(bolleanvar == true){ ~Random Code~)
☛in the while else the same way you can put another while loop, you can put any other type of code you want.
👉Bool: a variable of true or false, it's a logic variable.
👉Console.Clear() Method: Cleans everything that is in the console.
👉int.Parse(Console.ReadLine()): Tranforms a string you type in the console to an integer you can do maths.
👉Do While iteration Statement:it's the same thing of the while statement, but the code is executed atleast one time before the condition is given, exemple:
do{ ~Random code~ } while (~RandomCondition~);


💢Class 12
👉Sometimes it's necessary to manipulate strings, like formating it, or changing it.
👉BackSlash ("\"):Makes that in a string assignment, it ignores special characters that have a function in proggramation, making it abble to use these special characters as strings Example:
string random = "This is "random" at all"; <- The random wouldn't be in the string and there would be an error in the compiler, now string random = "This is \"random\" at all"; <- Would work because the "" are not being considered as special characters
☛You can use a backslash behind a backslash if you need a backslash as a string. example string1  = "Go to C:\\ drive;
☛You can also put @ to indicate that the backslashs will be used as strings and not as escape sequences, ex:string1 = @"Go to c:/drive";
👉SlashN (\n):it jumps one line from where is was put, and what is in front of it goes to the line jumped.
👉{} String Operator:You put numbers inside {} to indicate the order that will be replaced the strings you identify later, Ex:string1 = String.Format("{0}  {1}", "First, Second"), The first written will be the {0} and the second the{1} and like this eventually.
☛You can change the order if you want Ex:string1 = string.Format("{1}  {0}", "First, Second") <- The first which would show up in the console would be "Second".
☛You can use money values putting :C after the number inside the {} ({0:C}) and after put the money value, Ex: string1 = string.Format("{0:C}",102.32); <- The currency will be defined depending on your PC nacionality.
☛You can print commas to not confund the user with the values by putting :N after the number inside the {} ({0:N}) Ex: string1 = string.Format("{0:N}",10232); <- The value will be displayed 10,232
☛You can transform the number in porcentage putting :P after the number at {}, ({0:N) Ex: string1 = string.Format("{0:P}", .123);
☛You can make a cellphone value by using for Ex:string myString = string.Format("Phone Number:{0:(###) ####-####}" the 3 ### that are in the parenthesis are the DDD, and the other # are just the numbers of the cellphone with the "-".
in this is important to set the right quantity of # or the compiler can confund it with more numbers that are in the DDD. 
👉.Substring(6, 14):Grabs all the chars after a specific char position you determinate in the function itself, ex:(1) (6), and it can be also set a range, putting another number after the first, ex: (6,14)
👉.ToUpper():Makes the string capslocked
👉.Replace(" ", ""): Replaces all characters in a string with another characters, the first quotes will be the characters what will be replaced, The second quotes is what is gonna replace it.
👉.Remove(6, 14):Grabes all chars after the first number and before the second number and remove them, ex:(5,16);
👉.Trim():Removes all the blanket characters in the beggining of the string and in the end of the string (Only in the beggining and in the end).
👉.ToString(): makes a non-string variable type into a string.
👉When you're modifying a variable, what the compiller actually does is delete this variable, create another one with the same name and put it the values you modified.
👉.Append():Adds a variable or string that is inside the () in the method.

💢Class 13
👉Datetimes always start as integers.
👉DateTime.Now: assigning this code to something, the value will be the now time, and the now date, both depending on your country.
👉.ToShortDateString(): A method that causes the value be only the date, without the time.
👉.ToShortTimeString(): A method that causes the value be only the time, without the date.
👉.ToLongDateString():It says the date in form of names (ONLY THE DATE, NOT THE TIME) for example: domingo, 2 de janeiro de 2017.
👉.ToLongTimeString():It says the full time, including the seconds, ex:23:50:20
👉In c# you can continue calling methods together as long they keep being linked returning some data type. for ex: Console.WriteLine(myValue.AddDays(3).ToLongDateString()); the .ToLongDateString() indicates the data type.
👉.AddDays():add one or more days inside the parenthesis to an object or variable, you can decrease days by putting - in the number
👉.AddHours():add one or more hours inside the parenthesis to an object or variable, you can decrease hours by putting - in the number
👉In the datetimes, if the value of the object is only an integer, it's ok to print without converting, but if there's something more than an integer, you need to convert to a string.
👉TimeSpan data type:represents a time interval between x time or date, until y time or date.
👉.Now:Gets the now time or date or datetime.
👉.Subtract():subtracts with what is inside the parenthesis.
👉Ways to declare a date variable, object:DateTime tomorrow = new DateTime(2017, 07, 03) year month and day, another way:DateTime myBirthday = DateTime.Parse("16/01/2002") <- this converting string to datetime parsing it.

💢Class 14
👉Class: Is the blueprint of methods (in other words planning).18:27 04/07/2017
☛You use classes when you want to create patterns that you can instantiate many and many times with different values.
☛You can put return values into classes parameters,
☛Classes can have different createds properties inside of them, that will Later have its values set inside a created variable of the class type.
☛get;set;:are two properties to make the method, gettable, and settable.
👉Object:Something created as result of a blueprint or a pattern
👉Instance: To create an object of a class.
☛When you are creating a new instance of a class, you're like using a cookie cutter, with the cookie cutter each cookie you do is with a different shape, a differente size, a differente cream, that's how it works with class, you choose
distinct characteristics of the class to instantiate.
☛Is what makes the new class, be put in memory.

💢Class 15
👉Constructor: Simple methods that execute code at the moment when a new instance of a class is created, they always have the same name of the class, ex Car mycars = new Car() <- Car is the Constructor.
☛You could leave the constructor parenthesis empty with no problems, it just would do nothing.
👉The runtime in the c# always alocate a little bit of space to store a variable, with its value. For this the CLR searches for a memory space that is empty.
👉The computer always find things using their adresses, adresses in computer are hexadecimal.
👉When instantiating a new Class Object, the CLR will copy any of this intance values and put it into memory adress. Then you know where it puts that object. And them the adress is actually stored in the Operand of the Instance.
So the operand, is simply the reference for this instance adress that is the the PC Memory.
👉Memory: At some point, a certain thing in the memory will be no longer	useful, than the CLR automatically delete this thing from memory to you. When you try to put something in an already filled bucket in memory. That thing that before
was in the memory will corrupt. in C# this almost doesn't happen because the c# automatically handles with memory.
☛It deletes references that go out of scope and references that you apoint the value to null.
☛Sometimes apointing references to null will case you a problem that can be solved using deterministic finalization
👉This Keyword: refers to the instance of an object.
👉When creating an instance of a method (ex: Car myCar = new Car()) if in this class you created a method with the same name of the class itself, this method will be executed in the instance.
👉When creating a class method,1 you can even refer your values to the patterns create at the class, or you can create new vars in the parameters and define their values in the method call (overloaded).
👉Static: Makes you don't need to create an instance of a certain class to utilize a certain method.
☛Some classes are statics, which means you don't need to create an instance of it, however some classes are not static, meaning you need to create an instance of it.

💢Class 16
👉Scope: a space that there is code between the {}, a scope defined before another scope, can have their values used in scopes declared after those.
👉Private: It's a keyword used in a method or variable, THAT it just does something inside of a class and it can't be called by another class.
👉Public: It's a keyword used in a method or variable, it can be called by another class

💢Class 17:
👉Bin Directory: Contains Debug and Release folders.
👉Debug Folder: Where the debug stuff stays.
👉System Class: is a class that has all library of codes of visual studio.
 ☛:There are some classes you need to put the class System and put a dot right after it to identify this class. Ex: System.Net;
👉System.IO.File Class: creates a certain type of file in a directory.

💢Class 18:
👉Assembly: Are the dll where many classes are stored, that are a lot of kinds of assemblies, some are from the .NET some other companies do.
 ☛There are a lot of ways to install extern assemblies, even inside the visual studio itself.
👉DonwloadString method: it gets all the code of a website.
👉You can add new third assemblies, by hitting right click in the class name, click add and then reference, and locate the assembly.
👉Methods Variables can be defined in the return operators too.

💢Class 19:
*Collections: it's a compiled of integers, that can have different types, there are many kind of collections, but the main are: lists, generic lists and dictionaries

LINQ (Language-Integrated Query): 	
*List: The problem of old arraylist styles, is that they don't difference the type of arrays (int, string etc...), and it makes with it can't be executed in a foreach statement, because if you said to execute all the members of Class "Cars" of
one specific property, it would execute all of the list anyway and a error would come.
*Generic List: You can put whatever kind of integer you want, but you need to make them different, by putting an specific data type to each group.
declaration: List*<Car> myList = new List<Car>(); *The datatype. 
*Dictionary:There's a lot of words (key) with a lot of definitions (values)
*Key: The world itself we want to look up, should be unique to every dictionary.
*Value: can be of any datatype
*In a class instantiation itself, you can already set the values of the class properties if you want, by putting {} after the instantiation and defining each properties.
*You can instantiate instances into a collection right after creating, this would make it easier because you wouldn't need to keep putting thousands of .Add instancename.

💢 Class 20:
*LINQ(language integrated query syntax): It's what recovers data of a data font, for example, select only the cars that have the data of 2010, or the make bmw. There are 2 types of linqs:
*Query: the one you recovery information, by assigning the var to a sequence of data that recoveries information, without needing method parenthesis
*Method:The one you recovery information, by assigning the var to a linq condition statement, and right after it, you open parenthesis to put the linq condition.
*P in method linq: an instance of an collection.
*Var conotation: A type that says to the compiler discover what's the correct required data type.
*Orderby: makes the order be descending od scending. (in matter of number size)
*Lambda expression: ex (p => p.Make = "this"), this means that when were given an instance of a collection, only return those instances where Make = "this"
*TrueForAll: checks if all elements in a list are false or true.


💢 Class 21:
*Enumeration: data type that limits and constrains all possible values to only those that are valid and have meaning in the system.
 -The real values of an enumeration are numbers, but are translated to us as a name we give.
*Switch statements: they are used  to make a certain thing in an specific case of an specific enumeration
ex: case Status.Completed:
Console.ForegroundColor = ConsoleColor.White;
-The "default" of the switch statements, is like the "else" of the "if", which means that if any previous conditions were attended, the default case will be executed.

💢 Class 22:
*Exceptions: there are countless reasons for those to happen, files corrupt, or a folder/file is missing, and commonly it acess a database and doesn't find what it needs.
 -Putting wrong adresses in a input parameter could cause those as well.
*Try statement: tries a line of code and checks if there is any exception on it, if there is, it will go straight to a catch{}
*Catch statement: is the code that gets executed in case the try statement had any exception
*Finally statement: is the code that gets executed independently of anything

💢 Class 22:
